prometheanplanet.com 2016-06-08

# Privacy Policy - Promethean Planet

Privacy Policy For Promethean Planet.com and ClassFlow.com

 _Effective Date:  August 12, 2014  
_  
 **IMPORTANT:**  With respect to your use of [ClassFlow.com](http://www.classflow.com/), if you are a student in a primary or secondary school OR you are under the age of eighteen (18) years, you must get your parent or guardian to read these terms and agree to them on your behalf before you use ClassFlow.com or before you provide any information about yourself in the Service. This document is a Contract and it should be reviewed with your parent or guardian so that you both understand how the Service works and what restrictions or rules apply to your use of the Service.  

With respect to Promethean Planet, [www.prometheanplanet.com](http://www.prometheanplanet.com/), the Site does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register for use of the Site. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register or send any information about yourself to us or on the Site, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under the age 13 may provide any personal information to Promethean Planet. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us at privacy@prometheanworld.com  
ClassFlow.com (“ClassFlow” or the “Service") and PrometheanPlanet.com (“Planet” or the “Site”) are provided by Promethean Limited (“Promethean”, "we", or "us", or "our"). We are a limited company registered in England and Wales with our registered office at Promethean Limited, Promethean House, Lower Philips Road, Whitebirk Industrial Estate, Blackburn, Lancashire, BB1 5TH, United Kingdom. When we use the word “Service(s)”, we mean not only the ClassFlow.com website, but also all the other related websites, products, services, and applications made available by Promethean (including the ClassFlow Student App and the ClassFlow Teacher App available via the iTunes store and Android Play store). When we use the word “Site” we mean the PrometheanPlanet.com website. If you have any questions, comments, or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [support@ClassFlow.com](mailto:support@ClassFlow.com).

This Privacy Policy, together with the ClassFlow and Planet Cookies Policies, the Terms of Service, and Acceptable Use Policies referred to in this Privacy Policy, form a legally binding Contract between you and us (collectively referred to herein as the “Contract”). Please read them carefully before you start to use either the Service or the Site. By using either the Service or the Site you indicate that you accept these Terms of Service, Acceptable Use Policy, Cookies Policies and this Privacy Policy and you agree to be bound by and abide by the terms of all of them. If you do not agree to these terms and policies please do not use either the ClassFlow Service or the Planet Site. "You" or “your” is defined as an Individual User of the Service or the Site. An Individual User maybe a teacher/educator, a student, or a parent. Where applicable, “you” or “your” may also be defined as a school or school district or other educational institution otherwise known as an “Enterprise User”, with whom the Individual User is associated either as a student, teacher/educator, or parent of a student. Individual Users purchasing from, downloading from, or uploading/posting to our Service or the Site on behalf of an Enterprise User agree that they do so with the appropriate permissions and authority. The term “User(s)” will refer to Individual Users and Enterprise Users.

Remember that your use of Promethean's ClassFlow Service and Planet Site are at all times subject to the Terms of Service, which incorporates this Privacy Policy.  Any terms we use here without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Service.

### What is the Purpose of this Privacy Policy?

Promethean respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.  This Privacy Policy explains how Promethean collects, holds, uses and discloses any personal or other information that we collect from you and from third parties or that you otherwise provide to us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your personal and non-personal information and how we will treat it. This policy does not apply to third party Web sites or applications to which we provide links from our Service or from the Site.

“Personal Information” as used in this Privacy Policy means information or an opinion about an identified individual, whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not. This includes your name, names of family members, your address, your telephone number, your e-mail address, your screen name or user name, a photograph, video or audio file, information about a child or his/her parents, or personal unique identifiers such as your social security number (US persons only) or date of birth. It also includes sensitive information such as race or ethnic origin, political opinions, membership in political associations, physical or mental health or condition, membership in government program, philosophical beliefs, membership in a professional or trade association or union, sexual orientation or practices, criminal record, genetic information, and biometric information (“Sensitive Personal Information”).  
The information we collect and hold about you depends on who you are, including whether you are a teacher, student or parent.

### What Personal Information is collected from Users of the ClassFlow Service?  
What Personal Information is collected from Users of the Planet Site?

We collect and store the information that you knowingly enter on the Service or the site, whether via computer, mobile phone, or other wireless device or that you provide to us in any other way. This information may include, without limitation, Personal Information such as your name, user name, e-mail address, phone number, school affiliation and location, billing and payment information, and any other information necessary for us to provide our services. If the ClassFlow Service is obtained by an educational establishment for the use of its teachers/educators and students (an “Enterprise User”), that Customer may wish for the Service to integrate with the Customer’s Student Information System (SIS). In those instances, we will collect and store only that information from the Customer SIS which the Enterprise Customer provides to us and that is necessary for the purposes of providing the Service. The SIS may contain Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information about each student in the school or district including, but not limited to, parent’s names, students’ class schedules, students’ grades, students’ dates of birth, gender, race and students’ school identification numbers. By using the ClassFlow Service you agree to and authorize any such collection of Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information from the Enterprise User’s SIS for the purposes of providing the Service. Personal Information of Individual Users may also be provided by a teacher or parent or guardian. By using the ClassFlow Service you agree to and authorize this collection of information.

If we determine that we have collected Personal Information from or about a student without their required parental/guardian consent or that a student has provided us more Personal Information than we requested from him or her, we will take reasonable steps to destroy that information securely and as quickly as possible. If you believe that a student may have provided us personal information in violation of this paragraph, please contact us at [support@ClassFlow.com](mailto:support@ClassFlow.com).

### What does Promethean use my Personal Information for?

When you register an account on ClassFlow.com and PrometheanPlanet.com we collect some Personal Information such as your name and e-mail address which is used to (i) create your individual account, (ii) administer your use of the Service including responding to your requests for certain information and services, (iii) better understand your needs and interest, (iv) personalize and improve your Service, (v) provide or offer updates and product announcements (vi) tell you about opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you, (vii) provide you with information about the promotions, competitions, products, and services we offer (please see [https://www.classflow.com](https://www.classflow.com/) for the terms and conditions relating to any promotions and competitions associated with the Service and please see [www.prometheanplanet.com](http://www.prometheanplanet.com/) for the terms and conditions relating to any promotions and competitions associated with the Site), and or (vii) provide and share information with your school/employer, teacher and/or parent or guardian as applicable. We will display your Personal Information in your profile page and elsewhere on the Service or Site according to the preferences you set in your account. With respect to ClassFlow, your district, school, teacher(s) and parent/guardian (as applicable) may have access to your Personal Information through your profile page and the Service. You can review and revise your profile information at any time.

### To whom does Promethean disclose my Personal Information?

You may use a third party application to access or log on to your ClassFlow account or your Planet account such as Facebook or Google. Promethean is not responsible for what those third parties do with your information so you should make sure you trust the application and that it has a privacy policy acceptable to you. Promethean will not share your Personal Information with Facebook or Google without your consent.

We may disclose your Personal Information as required or authorized by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us; enforce or apply our Terms of Service, Acceptable Use Policy and other agreements (including to disclose Personal Information to law enforcement, your school or your employer); or protect the rights, property, or safety of Promethean, our employees, our Users, or others.

If Promethean or some or all of its assets were acquired or otherwise transferred, or in the unlikely event that Promethean would go out of business or enter bankruptcy, User information including Personal Information may be transferred to or acquired by a third party.

We may use certain trusted third party companies and individuals to help us provide, analyze and improve the Service, including but not limited to, data storage, maintenance services, database management, web analytics, payment processing and improvement of the Service’s features.  Information received and/or collected by ClassFlow is stored on servers owned by Amazon Web Services, Inc. located in the United States, and is subject to lawful access requests by authorities in the United States. Information received and/or collected on Promethean Planet is stored on servers owned by Gossamer Threads located in Canada. These trusted third parties may have access to your Personal Information only for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf and under obligations similar to those in this Privacy Policy. By way of example only, we may use one of our trusted third party companies to analyze, collect, and provide to us the e-mail addresses of all Users who have not used the Service or not logged into the Site in a certain time period.  If you are one of those Users, we may send you an e-mail telling you about a new feature we have added since you last visited the site or encouraging you to give us another try. Similarly, and by way of example only, we may use one of these trusted third parties to analyze, collect, and provide to us the e-mail addresses of all those Users who have uploaded/posted at least 30 User Submissions into the ClassFlow Service in the last six months.  If you are one of those Users, we might e-mail a survey to you in order to get your feedback on which features you like most or what you would like to see changed about the Service. Of course, should we send you direct marketing communications such as  those email examples provided above, you will always have the opportunity to easily unsubscribe or opt-out of receiving those communications by following the unsubscribe instructions on the email itself which shall be easy to understand and cost-free..  

### What other information is collected from Users of the ClassFlow Service?  
What other information is collected from Users of the Planet Site?

In addition to the information which you provide to us, we also automatically receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with the Service or the Site. For example, Promethean automatically receives and records usage information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, Promethean cookie information (see below), and the page you requested. We also record the details of your activity on the Service, and the number and frequency of visits to our site and its components including but not limited to, traffic data, location data, and the resources that you access.  If you contact us, we may also keep a record of that correspondence.  

When you download our ClassFlow mobile application, we automatically collect information on the type of device, name and version of the operating system, name and version of the application, whether the currently logged in User is a teacher, student, or other user type, the numerical mobile device user ID, as well as actions performed by the User in accessing the mobile application (“Mobile Usage Information,” which is considered part of “usage information” as described above). However, we do not ask you for, access or track any geographic-location-based information from your mobile device (i.e., any information regarding where your mobile device is located on the globe at a particular time) at any time while downloading or using our mobile applications. For clarity, this does not prevent us from asking you the school with which you are affiliated.

### What does Promethean use Other Information for?

Promethean or Promethean’s trusted third party companies described above, may collect information about your computer, including where available, your IP address, operating system, and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information (how groups of people use the Service). This is statistical data about our Users’ actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual. We may collect and analyze this aggregate data on how the Service or the Site is used for the purpose of improving and enhancing the Service or the Site as applicable thereby, increasing our Service’s or our Site’s functionality and user-friendliness.

In addition to data used in the aggregate, we may also collect individual User data for the purpose of determining how often you use the ClassFlow Service or Planet Site or don’t use the Service/Site or which features you use the most or use the least for the purpose of improving the Service/Site and improving your experience using the Service/Site. Additionally, individual usage of the system, including but not limited to individual IP addresses, may be analyzed on a case-specific basis to resolve a technical difficulty or to assist in resolving or investigating any misuse of the Service or misuse of the Site. Promethean may share the aggregate data collected with a third party but not any Personal Information about any individual User without your express permission. We may also use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile application and mobile site on your phone. The information collected for the purposes set forth in this paragraph is in a non-personally identifiable format.

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer or mobile device to enable our systems to recognize your computer or device and tell us how and when pages in our site are visited and by how many people.  To understand exactly what cookies are used on our ClassFlow Service, please click here to review our ClassFlow Cookies Policy. To understand exactly what cookies are used on our Planet Site click here to review our Promethean Planet Cookies Policy.Our third party service providers may also transmit cookies to your computer or device, to help provide you with an optimal online experience. The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by this Privacy Policy and we do not have access or control over such cookies.  

 _If You are a Student accessing the ClassFlow Service, the following additional provisions apply specifically to You:_

  * You are prohibited from using the Service unless you have been specifically directed to do so by your educational institution or by a teacher/educator at your educational institution.  If you have not been so directed, please stop using the Service.
  *  _In the event you are using the Service at the direction of a teacher/educator or your educational institution and you are in a primary or secondary school OR you are under the age of eighteen (18) years, your teacher or educational institution must obtain from your parent or guardian a written parental consent to the use of the Service before you use the Service._
  * You will only access the Service via the Learner App or through ClassFlow.com as a student user, and not as a teacher, parent, or any other category of user and only at the direction and guidance of your teacher/educator and or educational institution
  * You will only access the Service using the specific code or log in information (as applicable) given to you by your teacher/educator and or educational institution. You may not use any codes or log in information which you receive from other students or which you were not expressly authorized to use directly by your teacher/educator and or educational institution.

 _If You are accessing the ClassFlow Service as a Parent or Guardian (if applicable), the following additional provisions apply specifically to You:_

  * You will only access the Service using the parent access code (as applicable) provided to you by your child’s teacher and or educational institution.
  * You understand that by using the Service you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy and you are agreeing to these Terms both on your own behalf as well as on behalf of your child or children who use the Service.
  * We encourage you to avoid including unnecessary Personal Information about yourself, your children or others on the Service, and we encourage parents to talk with your children about not including sensitive or Personal Information in any resource or material used in connection with this Service.

 _If you are accessing the ClassFlow Service as a Teacher/Educator (where your educational institution has not obtained an institution-wide or enterprise license to use ClassFlow.com), the following additional provisions apply specifically to You:_

  * You represent and warrant that you have permission from your educational institution to enter into this Contract, to use the Service as part of your curriculum, and that you have the authority to bind your educational institution to this Contract.
  * If you teach in a primary or secondary school OR you teach students that are under the age of eighteen (18) years, under this privacy policy you agree to obtain from your students’ parent or guardian a written parental consent prior to your Students use of the Service or prior to you entering any student Personal Data in the Service. If you are located in the United States, you further represent and warrant that you are solely responsible for complying with the Child Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) which requires you to obtain advanced written consent from all parents or guardians whose children under the age of 13 will be accessing the Service. You must keep all consents on file and provide a copy to us upon our request. When obtaining such consent, you must also provide parents/guardians with a copy of or link to our Privacy Policy. For more information on COPPA, please see [www.ftc.gov/privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy). Click [here](https://classflow.com/sites/default/files/ClassFlow-Sample-Parental-Consent-1-14-2014.pdf) for a sample consent form.
  * If you are located in the United states, you further represent and warrant that you are solely responsible for complying with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) which requires you to obtain advanced written permission from all parents or guardians whose children are under the age of 18 in order to release any information from a student’s education record to a third party such as Promethean.  For more information on FERPA, please see http://www.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html.  
  * If you are located outside the United States, you are required to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy and all regulations and laws governing the privacy of children in your territory.  You represent and warrant that you are in compliance with all applicable data protection laws governing the protection of Personal Information including Sensitive Personal Information and the sharing of student education records.
  * We do not monitor, review or exercise any control over the resources uploaded or shared when using the Service (though we reserve the right to block resources or take down resources that we reasonably believe may subject Promethean or our Users to liability, see the ClassFlow Terms of Service regarding User Submissions and see the ClassFlow Acceptable Use Policy. Accordingly, Personal Information that you include as part of a User Submission on the Service is not governed by this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to avoid including Personal Information about yourself, your students or others in resources or lessons that will be shared or made public, and we encourage teachers to talk with their students about not including sensitive or Personal Information in any resource or material used in connection with this Service.

 _  
If You are accessing the ClassFlow Service on behalf of an Educational Institution (an Enterprise Customer), the following additional provisions apply specifically to You:_

  * If you are a primary or secondary school OR you teach students that are under the age of eighteen (18) years, under this privacy policy you agree to obtain from your students’ parent or guardian a written parental consent prior to your Students use of the Service or prior to your teachers entering any student Personal Data in the Service. If you are located in the United States, you further represent and warrant that you are solely responsible for complying with the Child Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) which requires you to obtain advanced written consent from all parents or guardians whose children under the age of 13 will be accessing the Service. You must keep all consents on file and provide a copy to us upon our request. When obtaining such consent, you must also provide parents/guardians with a copy of or link to our Privacy Policy. For more information on COPPA, please see [www.ftc.gov/privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy). Click [here](https://classflow.com/sites/default/files/ClassFlow-Sample-Parental-Consent-1-14-2014.pdf) for a sample consent form.
  * If you are located in the United states, you further represent and warrant that you are solely responsible for complying with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) which requires you to obtain advanced written permission from all parents or guardians whose children are under the age of 18 in order to release any information from a student’s education record to a third party such as Promethean.  For more information on FERPA, please see <http://www.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html>.
  * If you are located outside the United States, you are required to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy and you are required to comply with all regulations and laws governing the privacy of children in your territory.  You represent and warrant that you are in compliance with all applicable data protection laws governing the protection of Personal Information of children and the sharing of student education records.
  * You will only grant access codes to teachers/educators who are current employees of your educational institution. Upon termination of a teacher/educator’s employment with you, you will require such individual to return and cease using all access codes he or she has in his or her possession which have been provided to them by you. If at any time you learn a User of the Service claims to be affiliated with your educational institution who is not, in fact, affiliated with your educational institution, you will notify Promethean immediately.
  * You will only grant access codes to students who are currently enrolled in your educational institution.  Upon termination of the enrollment of the student, you will ensure that use of the Service by the student is canceled/terminated with respect to their affiliation with your educational institution.

### Is Information About Me Secure?

Promethean takes precautions to maintain the security and integrity of Personal Information it collects about you, including storage of your Personal Information on a secure servers behind multiple firewalls.

Promethean uses industry standard SSL (secure socket layer technology) encryption to transfer sensitive and Personal Information. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and although we take reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information, Promethean cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information managed by the ClassFlow Service or the Planet Site, whether transmitted to Promethean by you, the educational institution, or the teacher. Once we receive your information, we will use procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access. We consider these security safeguards to be reasonable in the circumstances.

By agreeing to the this Privacy Policy, you agree to use the ClassFlow Service and the Promethean Planet Site at your own risk, and agree (to the maximum extent permitted by law) that Promethean shall not be liable if a security breach occurs, if the ClassFlow Service or the Planet Site malfunctions, or if information is misused or mismanaged in any way to your detriment or the detriment of a third party, whether by Promethean, the educational institution, a teacher, or an unauthorized third party. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Service or the Site.

In order to access any Personal Information, you must set up an account which is protected by a password for your privacy and security. We also use coding practices which take steps to prevent attack on our Service from web browsers and malicious scripts, by processing all actions through several permission verifications checks.

You can help protect against unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

The ClassFlow Service and the Planet Site may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites (but you should read those third parties’ privacy policies to ensure you understand them). This Privacy Policy only governs information collected by Promethean via the ClassFlow Service and the Planet Site.

### Retention and Deletion of Personal Information

If you wish to cancel your ClassFlow account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, you may delete your account by contacting info@ClassFlow.com. If you wish to cancel your Promethean Planet account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, you may delete your account by contacting webmaster@prometheanworld.com. We may retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We will take reasonable steps to securely de-identify and destroy such information when it is no longer needed for those requirements. Upon cancelation of your ClassFlow account, to the extent that you have included any Personal Information in any User Submissions (see the ClassFlow Terms of Service regarding User Submissions), we will stop displaying your User Submissions to other Users (if applicable), but you understand and agree that it may not be possible to completely delete that content from the Service, and that your User Submissions may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent that they were copied or stored by other Users with whom you chose to share the User Submission. 

### Can I Update, Correct, or Delete Personal Information?

You may correct, update, or delete your information submitted to the ClassFlow Service by making the change on our account profile page or contacting [info@ClassFlow.com](mailto:info@ClassFlow.com).  Similarly you may correct, update, or delete your information submitted to the Promethean Planet site by making the change in y our account settings and profile page or contacting privacy@prometheanworld.com. We will respond to your request within thirty (30) days (or less, if required by law). If you otherwise ask us to correct, update, delete or change the Personal Information we hold about you, we will do so if we are satisfied that this is required.  If we decide not to change your Personal Information in the manner you have requested, we will advise you of this in writing and how you can complain if you are not satisfied with our decision. If you request a change to your Personal Information and we do not make that change, you may request that we note on our records that you requested a change to your Personal Information that was not made, and the reasons that change was not made.

Please be advised that requesting removal of or not providing certain information may result in you not receiving notification of updates to the Service or Site or other valuable information regarding your use of the Service or the Site. Failure to provide information requested by Promethean may mean that you are not able to access relevant features of the Service or Site.

You agree that you will keep the information on your account accurate, up to date and complete. 

### Can I access my Personal Information that Promethean holds about me?

You may seek access to any Personal Information Promethean holds about you (subject to any applicable exemptions). To seek access to the information we hold about you through the ClassFlow Service other than through your profile page, please contact [info@ClassFlow.com](mailto:info@ClassFlow.com).  To seek access to the information we hold about you through the Promethean Planet Site other than through your profile page, please contact privacy@prometheanworld.com. We will respond to your request within thirty (30) days. If we decide not to give you access, we will explain why to you in writing and how you can complain if you are not satisfied with our response.

### Will Promethean ever Change this Privacy Policy?

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time for any reason. If we make any material changes in the way we use Personal Information, we will notify you via email or by posting an announcement on the Service or the Site as applicable. By continuing to use the Service or the Site after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.  If a material change is made to this Privacy Policy with respect to the ClassFlow Service, a parent or guardian of a student who is accessing the ClassFlow Service must provide a new written parental/guardian consent to the child’s teacher and/or educational institution in order for the child to continue accessing the Service. The date this Privacy Policy was last revised is identified at the beginning of the Policy.

### What if I am from a Country other than the United States of America?

When you use the ClassFlow Service, you are consenting to have your data transferred to and processed in the United States.  When you use the Promethean Planet Site you are consenting to have your data transferred to and processed in Canada. It may be processed by staff who work for Promethean or staff who work for one of our third party suppliers. All of the servers used to provide the ClassFlow Service are currently located in the United States, and we aren’t able to process your information within the borders of any other country. All of the servers used to provide the Promethean Planet Site are currently located in Canada, and we aren’t able to process your information within the borders of any other country. Given this limitation, if your use of the Service or Site or disclosure of certain information to Promethean (or to our third party service providers) would violate any law that is applicable to you, your right to use the Service/Site and/or disclose such information is revoked, as it is wherever use of the Service or Site is prohibited by law.

### What if I have a Question About this Privacy Policy or a Complaint?

If you have a complaint, question or a concern about the information set forth in this Privacy Policy or about how we have handled your Personal Information with respect to your use of the ClassFlow Service, please contact us at [support@ClassFlow.com](mailto:support@ClassFlow.com). If you have a complaint, question or a concern about the information set forth in this Privacy Policy or about how we have handled your Personal Information with respect to your use of the Promethean Planet Site, please contact us at [webmaster@prometheanworld.com](mailto:webmaster@prometheanworld.com). We will try and deal with all complaints, questions and concerns within a reasonable period.      

If you are an Australian resident and you are not satisfied with how we have resolved your complaint, you can contact the Australian Federal Privacy Commissioner to make a complaint. For more information go to [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/).  
A copy of this Privacy Policy will be available free of charge on our websites, www.classflow.com and [www.prometheanplanet.com](http://www.prometheanplanet.com/), or by contacting us at [info@ClassFlow.com](mailto:info@ClassFlow.com) or privacy@prometheanworld.com.
